<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NXGEN Tech Blog on NXGEN - Tech Blog</title><link>https://nxgen.tech/</link><description>Recent content in NXGEN Tech Blog on NXGEN - Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://nxgen.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering CPU Configuration in QEMU: A Deep Dive into Virtual Development Environments</title><link>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/19/mastering-cpu-configuration-in-qemu-a-deep-dive-into-virtual-development-environments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/19/mastering-cpu-configuration-in-qemu-a-deep-dive-into-virtual-development-environments/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Learn how to properly configure CPU features in virtualized development environments using QEMU, with specific focus on compatibility with demanding applications like Unreal Engine 5. This guide covers common pitfalls and their solutions when setting up high-performance virtual machines for development work.&lt;/p>

&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#introduction" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Virtualization has become an integral part of modern development workflows, offering flexibility and isolation that traditional bare-metal setups cannot match. However, achieving optimal performance and compatibility in virtualized environments often requires careful configuration, particularly when dealing with CPU features and specialized software like Unreal Engine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unreal Engine 5.5: Next-Gen Rendering and Performance</title><link>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/16/unreal-engine-5.5-next-gen-rendering-and-performance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/16/unreal-engine-5.5-next-gen-rendering-and-performance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Explore the cutting-edge features in Unreal Engine 5.5, including the revolutionary MegaLights system, advanced ray tracing capabilities, and bindless rendering optimizations. This article will provide insights for developers looking to leverage these next-generation rendering capabilities.&lt;/p>

&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="technical-overview">Technical Overview&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#technical-overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As an experienced game developer focusing on advanced graphics and programming, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to explore the latest Unreal Engine 5.5 release. This version brings significant improvements to rendering capabilities, performance optimizations, and developer workflows. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the most impactful features from a technical perspective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building an Audiobook Processor: Splitting and Converting M4B Files for Car Audio</title><link>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/10/building-an-audiobook-processor-splitting-and-converting-m4b-files-for-car-audio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/10/building-an-audiobook-processor-splitting-and-converting-m4b-files-for-car-audio/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Learn how to build a Python script that processes M4B audiobook files into smaller, more manageable MP3 chunks while preserving audio quality and providing flexible customization options.&lt;/p>

&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="the-challenge-car-audio-and-audiobooks">The Challenge: Car Audio and Audiobooks&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#the-challenge-car-audio-and-audiobooks" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Modern audiobooks often come in M4B format, which while great for dedicated audiobook players, can present challenges when used with simpler audio systems like car stereos. I recently faced this exact problem: I had a lengthy audiobook I wanted to listen to during my commute, but my car&amp;rsquo;s audio system had two major limitations:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to My UI Programming Journey in Unreal Engine</title><link>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/09/welcome-to-my-ui-programming-journey-in-unreal-engine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nxgen.tech/blog/2024/11/09/welcome-to-my-ui-programming-journey-in-unreal-engine/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Welcome to my technical blog focusing on advanced UI programming in Unreal Engine, performance optimization techniques, and cutting-edge gaming technology analysis.&lt;/p>

&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="welcome-to-the-engineering-frontier">Welcome to the Engineering Frontier&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#welcome-to-the-engineering-frontier" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After years of pushing the boundaries of UI programming in Unreal Engine, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to share my insights, discoveries, and technical deep-dives with the game development community. This blog will serve as a technical repository of advanced programming techniques, performance optimizations, and analysis of emerging technologies in game development.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>